<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>post on Franck Cornu</title><link>https://www.franckcornu.com/tags/post/</link><description>Recent content in post on Franck Cornu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright Franck Cornu @ 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.franckcornu.com/tags/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use TailwindCSS with SPFx</title><link>https://www.franckcornu.com/post/using-tailwindcss-with-spfx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.franckcornu.com/post/using-tailwindcss-with-spfx/</guid><description>The GitHub solution showcasing the integration is available here: https://github.com/FranckyC/spfx-tailwind-sample/tree/develop To handle CSS customizations, the SharePoint framework comes with a prebuilt mechanism in its toolchain. Basically, all SASS or CSS stylesheets can be treated as TypeScript modules (ex: mycomponent.module.scss). This way, you can directly reference classes in your components using a styles variable imported from the generated .</description></item><item><title>New sort feature with the 4.6.0 PnP Modern Search version!</title><link>https://www.franckcornu.com/post/modern-search-overview-sort-control/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.franckcornu.com/post/modern-search-overview-sort-control/</guid><description>Since the 4.6.0 version of the PnP Modern Search solution, you can now configure sort fields for SharePoint/Microsoft Search data sources for both default sort and user sort (i.e sort results from the UI). As a result the previous &amp;ldquo;Edit sort order&amp;rdquo; option for data sources has been renamed to &amp;ldquo;Edit sort settings&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>PnP Modern Search: focus on item selection feature</title><link>https://www.franckcornu.com/post/modern-search-focus-item-selection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.franckcornu.com/post/modern-search-focus-item-selection/</guid><description>In the latest release of PnP Modern Search (4.5.3), we&amp;rsquo;ve added the ability to connect two Search Results Web Parts together. It went quite unnoticed at the time but it actually unlocks a lot of cool new scenarios requiring dynamic filtering, for instance, to build dynamic dashboards experiences. In this article I will review how this works and how you can benefit from this feature for your search pages.</description></item></channel></rss>