<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Franck Cornu</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/</link><description>Recent content on Franck Cornu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright Franck Cornu @ 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.franckcornu.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monitor your Copilot declarative agents using TypeSpec and Application Insights</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/add-app-insights-procode-copilot-da/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/add-app-insights-procode-copilot-da/</guid><description>Monitor your Copilot declarative agents using TypeSpec and Application Insights The complete example is available on GitHub: https://github.com/FranckyC/copilot-pro-dev-samples/tree/main/samples/da-typespec-appinsights
Why monitoring? For those developing and deploying Copilot declarative agents, you&amp;rsquo;re likely familiar with the challenge of obtaining meaningful usage metrics. Since agent development is inherently empirical and iterative—often involving several cycles of deployment and refinement—it is essential for business owners to understand how their agents are performing before and after deployment to end users.</description></item><item><title>Build a company wide documentation platform with Azure Application Gateway and Microsoft Search</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/manage-org-documentation-app-gateway/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/manage-org-documentation-app-gateway/</guid><description>Managing technical knowledge within a company, especially in large organizations with numerous teams, can be incredibly challenging. Often, project or technical content that could benefit various teams is scattered across multiple locations and presented in diverse formats. This dispersion makes the information difficult to access, hard to navigate, and, in some cases, completely hidden from others.</description></item><item><title>Use the Microsoft Graph API as a Copilot plugin for a declarative agent</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/copilot-graph-api-qna-plugin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/copilot-graph-api-qna-plugin/</guid><description>Recently, I came across an interesting use case building an HR agent allowing employees to ask common questions about company internal policies. These policies were made available to Copilot through a custom Graph Connector. However, during our tests, we realized for some questions, Copilot was struggling answering correctly even though answers were present in FAQ documents alongside the policy itself.</description></item><item><title>Leverage PnP Modern Search Core components and Microsoft Search in your Docusaurus documentation</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/integrate-components-with-docusaurus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/integrate-components-with-docusaurus/</guid><description>In this blog post, I show you how to integrate the PnP Modern Search Core components into your enterprise Docusaurus documentation sites to add search capability.
The GitHub solution associated to this post is available here: https://github.com/microsoft-search/pnp-modern-search-core-components/tree/main/samples/docusaurus
What is Docusaurus? Docusaurus (https://docusaurus.io/) is a static site generator created by Facebook and implemented with React.</description></item><item><title>Hey Copilot, what about my metadata?</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/copilot-studio-and-metata/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/copilot-studio-and-metata/</guid><description>In this blog post, I wanted to share with you a use case I came across regarding my recent experience with Copilot Studio.
DISCLAIMER I&amp;rsquo;m not an &amp;ldquo;AI expert&amp;rdquo; by any means, just a developer who consumes AI services which is not quite the same :D.
IMPORTANT UPDATE (23/08/2024) I had the confirmation from Microsoft that custom Copilots built through Copilot Studio do not leverage the user or tenants semantic index.</description></item><item><title>Use TailwindCSS with SPFx</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/using-tailwindcss-with-spfx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/using-tailwindcss-with-spfx/</guid><description>The GitHub solution showcasing the integration is available here: https://github.com/FranckyC/spfx-tailwind-sample/tree/develop To handle CSS customizations, the SharePoint framework comes with a prebuilt mechanism in its toolchain. Basically, all SASS or CSS stylesheets can be treated as TypeScript modules (ex: mycomponent.module.scss). This way, you can directly reference classes in your components using a styles variable imported from the generated .</description></item><item><title>New sort feature with the 4.6.0 PnP Modern Search version!</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/modern-search-overview-sort-control/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/modern-search-overview-sort-control/</guid><description>Since the 4.6.0 version of the PnP Modern Search solution, you can now configure sort fields for SharePoint/Microsoft Search data sources for both default sort and user sort (i.e sort results from the UI). As a result the previous &amp;ldquo;Edit sort order&amp;rdquo; option for data sources has been renamed to &amp;ldquo;Edit sort settings&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Programmatically synchronize content types to a site from content type hub</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/synchronize_content_types_from_hub/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 18:24:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/synchronize_content_types_from_hub/</guid><description>The new SharePoint Online content type hub is a really geat feature to ensure a standardized information architecture across the company. Compared to the previous version, a lot of improvements has been made, especially the synchronization process with consumer sites which is now much faster and convenient.
However, to be able to add content types in a library or list coming from the hub in a specific SharePoint site, you must first synchronize them.</description></item><item><title>PnP Modern Search: focus on item selection feature</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/modern-search-focus-item-selection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/modern-search-focus-item-selection/</guid><description>In the latest release of PnP Modern Search (4.5.3), we&amp;rsquo;ve added the ability to connect two Search Results Web Parts together. It went quite unnoticed at the time but it actually unlocks a lot of cool new scenarios requiring dynamic filtering, for instance, to build dynamic dashboards experiences. In this article I will review how this works and how you can benefit from this feature for your search pages.</description></item><item><title>New year, new blog!</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/new-year-new-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 18:24:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/new-year-new-blog/</guid><description>Remember thecollaborationcorner.com? Wel&amp;hellip;it&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since my last blog post. Actually I closed my previous blog (thecollaborationcorner.com) almost 3 years ago due to a lack of time and motivation. After a quite busy period for me since the last two past years (two new born in 3 years!), I finally decided to go forward and open a blog again, but this time using cool new tools.</description></item><item><title>PnP Modern Search course is now available!</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/new-pnp-modern-course/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 18:24:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/post/new-pnp-modern-course/</guid><description>Finally. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while I wanted to create this content but now it is live! I&amp;rsquo;m glad to announce I&amp;rsquo;ve released a complete course about usage and configuration for the PnP Modern Search solution. This course arrives with the latest 4.5.4 version and should help you to use the solution at its full potential.</description></item><item><title>Elements</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/elements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/elements/</guid><description>H1 Heading H2 Heading H3 Heading H4 Heading H5 Heading H6 Heading Paragraph Did you come here for something in particular or just general Riker-bashing? And blowing into maximum warp speed, you appeared for an instant to be in two places at once. We have a saboteur aboard. We know you’re dealing in stolen ore.</description></item><item><title>Franck Cornu</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/author/franck-cornu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/author/franck-cornu/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been SharePoint &amp;amp; Microsoft 365 consultant for almost 10 years now and Office Development MVP, I’ve worked for several companies in many fields especially intranet solutions. Involved in the Pattern &amp;amp; Practices initiative, I’m the main author of the PnP Modern Search solution.
You won&amp;rsquo;t find any better source of information than me about this solution ;)</description></item><item><title>Hello there, I am Franck Cornu</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/about/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been SharePoint &amp;amp; Microsoft 365 consultant for almost 10 years now and Office Development MVP, I’ve worked for several companies in many fields especially intranet solutions. Involved in the Pattern &amp;amp; Practices initiative, I’m the main author of the PnP Modern Search solution.
You won&amp;rsquo;t find any better source of information than me about this solution ;)</description></item><item><title>Homepage</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/home/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Homepage Full</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/full/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/full/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Homepage Full Left</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/full-left/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/full-left/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Homepage Full Right</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/full-right/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/full-right/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Homepage Grid</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/grid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/grid/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Homepage Grid Left</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/grid-left/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/grid-left/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Homepage Grid Right</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/grid-right/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/grid-right/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Homepage List</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/list/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Homepage List Left</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/list-left/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/list-left/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Homepage List Right</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/list-right/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/homepage/list-right/</guid><description/></item><item><title>No Search Found</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/404/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/404/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Search Results</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/search/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Talk To Me Anytime :)</title><link>https://blog.franckcornu.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.franckcornu.com/contact/</guid><description>Ask Us Anything Or just Say Hi, Rather than just filling out a form, Sleeknote also offers help to the user with links directing them to find additional information or take popular actions.</description></item></channel></rss>